<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Sample Tisch content -->
<input xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcadesc="http://nils.lib.tufts.edu/dcadesc/"
   xmlns:dcatech="http://nils.lib.tufts.edu/dcatech/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:admin="http://nils.lib.tufts.edu/dcaadmin/" xmlns:ac="http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/"
   xmlns:rel="info:fedora/fedora-system:def/relations-external#"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
   <digitalObject>
      <file>TIER_JAdolescRes_Dec292016.pdf</file>
      <rel:hasModel>info:fedora/cm:Text.PDF</rel:hasModel>
      <dc:title>Rapid Repeat Birth: Intersections Between Meaning-Making and Situational Support
         Among Multiparous Adolescent Mothers.</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Reddy, Julia.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Mistry, Jayanthi.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Jacobs, Francine Helene.</dc:creator>
      <dc:description>This study examined interpretations of motherhood among adolescents who have
         experienced rapid repeat births (second births within 24 months of the primiparous birth)
         Analyses of participants' descriptions of their transitions to motherhood indicate four
         modal narratives that vary along two axes: the adoption of a motherhood identity, and the
         nature (or stability) of relational support available. By using subjective perceptions of
         motivation, stability, and feelings of competence, this study linked intrapersonal
         meaning-making with situational sources of support to describe various pathways through
         repeat adolescent childbearing in a way that both confirms and enriches extant literature.
         The implications of this study instruct home visiting programs and other interventions
         designed to forestall repeat pregnancies by elucidating pathways of reinforcement or
         increased risk inherent in some maternal trajectories. Following this logic, interventions
         directed at improving outcomes for young mothers and their children would do well to
         consider the interplay between internal meaning-making, relational support, and the
         transformative power of adopting the mother identity.</dc:description>
      <dc:description>Original file name: TIER_JAdolescRes_Dec292016</dc:description>
      <dc:bibliographicCitation>Reddy, J., Misty, J., Jacobs, F. Rapid repeat birth: Intersections
         between meaning-making and situational support among multiparous adolescent mothers.
         Journal of Adolescent Research. Prepublished December 29, 2016,
         https://doi.org/10.1177/0743558416684956.</dc:bibliographicCitation>
      <dcterms:isPartOf>Tufts University faculty scholarship.</dcterms:isPartOf>
      <dc:publisher>Tufts University. Tisch Library.</dc:publisher>
      <dcterms:date>2017.</dcterms:date>
      <dc:date.created>2017-08-16T09:19:29.748-04:00</dc:date.created>
      <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dcadesc:subject>Teenage mothers.</dcadesc:subject>
      <dcadesc:subject>Motherhood.</dcadesc:subject>
      <dcadesc:corpname>Tufts University. Eliot-Pearson Department of Child
         Study.</dcadesc:corpname>
      <dcterms:license>Signed TDL form from Rebecca Fauth on behalf of TIER 8/3/17. Sage allows
         deposit of AM in IR on acceptance:
         https://us.sagepub.com/en-us/nam/journal-author-archiving-policies-and-re-use
         (https://perma.cc/7NE7-YUSJ)</dcterms:license>
      <dc:rights>https://sites.tufts.edu/dca/about-us/research-help/reproductions-and-use/</dc:rights>
      <admin:steward>tisch</admin:steward>
      <ac:name>amay02</ac:name>
      <ac:comment>FacultyScholarshipIngest: 2017-08-16T09:19:29.748-04:00; Tisch manages metadata
         and binary.</ac:comment>
      <admin:displays>dl</admin:displays>
      <admin:embargo/>
   </digitalObject>
   <digitalObject>
      <file>TIER_AmJOrthopsychiatry_Vol86_1_.pdf</file>
      <rel:hasModel>info:fedora/cm:Text.PDF</rel:hasModel>
      <dc:title>Patterns of Depression Among Adolescent Mothers: Resilience Related to Father
         Support and Home Visiting Program.</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Easterbrooks, M. Ann.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Kotake, Chie.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Raskin, Maryna.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Bumgarner, Erin.</dc:creator>
      <dc:description>The negative consequences of maternal depression are a major public health
         concern, both for mothers and for their children. Despite the high prevalence of depression
         among adolescent mothers, little is known about the patterns of adolescent mothers'
         depression in the early parenting years. The present study examined mothers' depression
         during the first 2 years following childbirth in a sample of 428 young mothers (20 or
         younger at first childbirth) who were participants in a randomized controlled trial of a
         home visiting parenting support program. Depressive symptoms were assessed using the
         self-reported Center for Epidemiological Studies Depression Scale (CES-D) Mothers were
         classified into groups based on whether their depressive symptoms were below or above the
         cutoff for clinically significant symptomatology. Depression groups (stable nondepressed,
         stable depressed, remitted depression) were associated with variations in mothers'
         satisfaction with support from the baby's father and enrollment in the home visiting
         program. Maternal depression was more likely to remit when mothers were satisfied with
         father support; assignment to the home visiting program was associated with mothers
         remaining mentally healthy. Results have clinical and policy implications for prevention
         and intervention programs. ©American Psychological Association, 2016. This paper is not the
         copy of record and may not exactly replicate the authoritative document published in the
         APA journal. Please do not copy or cite without author's permission. The final article is
         available, upon publication, at: http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/ort0000093.</dc:description>
      <dc:description>Original file name: TIER_AmJOrthopsychiatry_Vol86(1)</dc:description>
      <dc:bibliographicCitation>Easterbrooks, M. A., Kotake, C., Raskin, M., &amp; Bumgarner, E.
         (2016). Patterns of depression among adolescent mothers: Resilience related to father
         support and home visiting program. American Journal of Orthopsychiatry, 86(1), 61-68.
         http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/ort0000093.</dc:bibliographicCitation>
      <dcterms:isPartOf>Tufts University faculty scholarship.</dcterms:isPartOf>
      <dc:publisher>Tufts University. Tisch Library.</dc:publisher>
      <dcterms:date>2016.</dcterms:date>
      <dc:date.created>2017-08-16T09:19:29.748-04:00</dc:date.created>
      <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dcadesc:subject>Teenage mothers.</dcadesc:subject>
      <dcadesc:subject>Depression, Mental.</dcadesc:subject>
      <dcadesc:corpname>Tufts University. Eliot-Pearson Department of Child
         Study.</dcadesc:corpname>
      <dcterms:license>Signed TDL form from Rebecca Fauth on behalf of TIER 8/3/17. APA permits
         posting of AM after acceptance: http://www.apa.org/pubs/authors/posting.aspx
         (https://perma.cc/5XKX-XFEK)</dcterms:license>
      <dc:rights>https://sites.tufts.edu/dca/about-us/research-help/reproductions-and-use/</dc:rights>
      <admin:steward>tisch</admin:steward>
      <ac:name>amay02</ac:name>
      <ac:comment>FacultyScholarshipIngest: 2017-08-16T09:19:29.748-04:00; Tisch manages metadata
         and binary.</ac:comment>
      <admin:displays>dl</admin:displays>
      <admin:embargo/>
   </digitalObject>
   <digitalObject>
      <file>TIER_JFamPsychol_Vol30_3_.pdf</file>
      <rel:hasModel>info:fedora/cm:Text.PDF</rel:hasModel>
      <dc:title>Relationship types among adolescent parents participating in a home-visiting
         program: A latent-transition analysis.</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Raskin, Maryna.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Fosse, Nathan E.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Fauth, Rebecca.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Bumgarner, Erin.</dc:creator>
      <dc:creator>Easterbrooks, M. Ann.</dc:creator>
      <dc:description>Young parents (less than 25 years of age) have been shown to have especially
         low rates of father involvement and union stability. However, research has also shown that
         parenting experiences of young fathers may not be uniform. There is a need for more
         research that assesses both the multidimensionality of relationship typologies and their
         temporality. Using a large longitudinal sample of low-income, young mothers enrolled in a
         randomized control study of a home-visitation program (n = 704; 61% program, 39% control),
         we evaluated how mother-father relationship dynamics changed over time. Ten mother-reported
         indicators of relationships (e.g., coresidence, marital status, types of father support)
         were used to conduct a latent-class analysis of relationship types. A 4-class solution was
         identified at each time point: Single Parent, Supportive Nonresident Partner, Supportive
         Resident Partner, and Questioning/Ambivalent Coupling. Latent-transition analyses were used
         to evaluate stability of relationships across 2 years. At each transition, a large
         proportion of women moved from one relationship class to another, indicating heterogeneity
         in relationship dynamics of adolescent parents. Results revealed the potential of a
         home-visiting program targeted at young parents to favorably promote more stable and
         supportive mother-father relationships and coparenting arrangements. ©American
         Psychological Association, 2016. This paper is not the copy of record and may not exactly
         replicate the authoritative document published in the APA journal. Please do not copy or
         cite without author's permission. The final article is available, upon publication, at:
         http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/fam0000164.</dc:description>
      <dc:description>Original file name: TIER_JFamPsychol_Vol30(3)</dc:description>
      <dc:bibliographicCitation>Raskin, M., Fosse, N. E., Fauth, R. C., Bumgarner, E., &amp;
         Easterbrooks, M. A. (2016). Relationship types among adolescent parents participating in a
         home-visiting program: A latent-transition analysis. Journal of Family Psychology, 30(3),
         375-385. http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/fam0000164</dc:bibliographicCitation>
      <dcterms:isPartOf>Tufts University faculty scholarship.</dcterms:isPartOf>
      <dc:publisher>Tufts University. Tisch Library.</dc:publisher>
      <dcterms:date>2016.</dcterms:date>
      <dc:date.created>2017-08-16T09:19:29.748-04:00</dc:date.created>
      <dc:type>Text</dc:type>
      <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
      <dcadesc:subject>Parents.</dcadesc:subject>
      <dcadesc:subject>Fathers.</dcadesc:subject>
      <dcadesc:corpname>Tufts University. Eliot-Pearson Department of Child
         Study.</dcadesc:corpname>
      <dcterms:license>Signed TDL form from Rebecca Fauth on behalf of TIER 8/3/17. APA permits
         posting of AM after acceptance: http://www.apa.org/pubs/authors/posting.aspx
         (https://perma.cc/5XKX-XFEK)</dcterms:license>
      <dc:rights>https://sites.tufts.edu/dca/about-us/research-help/reproductions-and-use/</dc:rights>
      <admin:steward>tisch</admin:steward>
      <ac:name>amay02</ac:name>
      <ac:comment>FacultyScholarshipIngest: 2017-08-16T09:19:29.748-04:00; Tisch manages metadata
         and binary.</ac:comment>
      <admin:displays>dl</admin:displays>
      <admin:embargo/>
   </digitalObject>
</input>
